RUBEN OTERO LAMELA

PERSONAL STATEMENT:

Specialised in customer service with 10 years' experience in this field, resolving problems and adapting to different customers politely and with confidence. A calm, positive attitude which enables prioritizing objectives, communicating effectively, setting concrete expectations and maintaining control. Accommodating customer needs through common sense and attention to detail. Extensive knowledge of recruitment, training and development of staff.

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES:

German (A2)
Fluent in English (C1)
Fluent in Spanish (Mother Tongue)
Years of experience in Customer Service
Excellent team player
Good skills in MS Office

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:

02.2022 - Present Bus Driver. Reuter Reisen, Germany

- Transporting over 60 passengers daily safely along prescribed routes according to tight schedules.
- Assisting passengers with disabilities and other physical issues in boarding and exiting bus to promote passenger safety.
- Providing tourists with information and helping them finding the best connection to their desired destination.
- Building good rapport with customers on a daily basis and always assisting them when necessary.

03.2020 - 02.2022 FOH Manager. Marportsunbeach S.L Beach bar Restaurant. Spain

- Mananging the "Google My Business" accout of the Beachbar in order to advertise the venue, and make it a reference for customers from all over the world.
- Particiapting in the creation of the menu.
- Sampling drinks and tapas to attract more customers.
- Controlling stock levels and placing orders.
- Ensuring Health & Safety as well as hygiene procedures & standards are maintained.
- Training new members of staff on the Bar, Kitchen and Floor.
- Setting high standards and creating a solid structure to maintain the business afloat and make it thrive in the following years.

01.2019 - 01.2020 Administrative Officer. HMRC (Surge Rapid Response Team)

- Recruitment of Staff for different sectors of HMRC.
- Managing casework from a variety of different departments.
- Customer Suport over the phone, face to face, through letters/emails or using social media.
- Developing collaborative relationships with colleagues throughout Government.
- Assisting with high profile 'rapid response' deployments, and predictable peaks in demand.
- Helping to foster a 'continuous improvement' ethos throughout the team.

06.2012 - 11.2018 FOH Team Member, FOH Manager. Wagamama Cardiff Library, United Kingdom

- Ensuring Health & Safety and also hygiene procedures & standards are maintained.
- Responsible for recruiting using an internal applicat tracking system.
- Running interviews, trial shifts and inductions.
- Training & developing managers, team leaders and FOH team members.
- Reducing business costs by improving retencion and engagement of the staff.
- Looking closely at the KPIs of the restaurant and elavorating reports for the Area Managers.
- Dealing with complex issues throught the shift and resolving problems in order to improve the service and increase sales.
- Maximising all business opportunities to drive sales and meet targets.
- Organising the daily and weekly rotas for the Restaurant's staff.
- Controlling stock levels and placing orders through fourthfnb.
- Daily Staff Briefing Session.
- Dealing with customer complaints through a CRM System.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS:

09.2021 – ongoing	A1-C1 German language course Online.
09.2018 - 06.2019	NVQ in Customer Service and Management Level 3. Babcock. United Kingdom.
09.2014 – 06.2015	Cambridge English: Advanced certificate (CAE), Cardiff and Vale College, United Kingdom.
09.2005 – 06.2007	Diploma in Computer System (Hardware and Software) Seresco, Oviedo, Spain.
09.2003 – 06.2005	A-Level equivalent ('Bachillerato') in History, Latin, Economics, English, French and Philosophy. IES La Eria and IES Dna Jimena, Asturias, Spain.